<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Experience on Himanshu Shah</title>
    <link>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Experience on Himanshu Shah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 09:33:39 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Viant Technology - Full Stack Intern</title>
      <link>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/viant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 09:33:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/viant/</guid>
      <description>Responsibilities/Accomplishments As a Full Stack Intern in the Platform team I -
Developed a video-to-audio conversion microservice to enhance ad campaign performance using creatives in not only video but also audio ad placements, achieving an estimated `15%` lift in revenue. Used `AWS Lambda`, `MediaConvert`, `SNS`, and `DynamoDB`. Teamed up with another intern to automate the process of adding new third-party user segments using `Angular`, `Golang`, `AWS APIGateway`, and `S3`, saving `8+` engineer hours per use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visible Alpha - SE 2</title>
      <link>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/va-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 19:38:10 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/va-2/</guid>
      <description>Responsibilities/Accomplishments After 1.5 years at Visible Alpha, I was promoted to the Software Engineer 2 position. My accomplishments during this time were -
Added Snowflake as a data delivery channel using `Falcon` and `MySQL`, increasing revenue by `45%` and reducing the customer’s Time to Value. Revamped the file dispatcher service to reduce the number of open SSH connections by `5x`, increasing product scalability. Built APIs to reduce the average Tech-Support turnaround time by `80%` from `10` to `2` minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visible Alpha - SE 1</title>
      <link>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/va-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 19:07:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/va-1/</guid>
      <description>Responsibilities/Accomplishments As a Software Engineer in the Data feed and APIs team, I -
Migrated the existing monolithic ETL application to microservices, delivering high-volume, real-time data with low latency to clients, using `Django`, `MongoDB`, and `Redis`, driving `$2 million` in revenue. Reduced the ETL app file dispatch latency by `~80%` using `RabbitMQ` and `Celery` for async task execution (60 to 10 seconds). Added `REST APIs` and `AWS S3` as data delivery channels to ease data consumption for customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IIT Bombay</title>
      <link>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/iit-bombay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 16:58:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/iit-bombay/</guid>
      <description>About As a Research Intern, I was working alongside Anshuman Dhuliya, a PhD student at IIT Bombay, on his project Synergistic Program ANalyzer (SPAN). My role was to contribute to the Front-end of SPAN - to create a source-to-source compiler that takes a high-level specification as input and transpiles it into its Python equivalent.
Problem SPAN required data flow analyses as an input and in Python language to apply those optimizations to an input program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastek</title>
      <link>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/mastek/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 03:57:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/mastek/</guid>
      <description>Problem Mastek was using an internal help-desk application for their employees to log trouble tickets. This help-desk application was Desktop app and was quite cumbersome and difficult to use. Moreover, in certain situations, such as malfunctioning of keyboard or mouse, it became extremely difficult to raise a ticket. Employees had to log in to their PCs every time to view the ticket status.
Goal To improve the overall user experience of Mastek&amp;rsquo;s internal help-desk application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
