<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Experience on Himanshu Shah</title>
    <link>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Experience on Himanshu Shah</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 09:33:39 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Viant Technology - Full Stack Intern</title>
      <link>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/viant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 09:33:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/viant/</guid>
      <description>Responsibilities/Accomplishments As a Full Stack Intern in the Platform team I -
Automated the manual process of adding third-party segments to the database by adding an upload option in the UI using Angular creating a new microservice in Golang using AWS Lambda, APIGateway, and S3; saved 6+ engineer hours per week Developing a feature for transcoding videos to audio using AWS MediaConvert, SNS, DynamoDB, and EventBridge, increasing the bid eligibility for clients’ ad campaigns and thereby increasing the generated revenue Contributed to the architecture for the Video-to-Audio Conversion project Leveraged Go Generics to make it easier to add/fetch objects from DynamoDB </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visible Alpha - SE 2</title>
      <link>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/va-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 19:38:10 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/va-2/</guid>
      <description>Responsibilities/Accomplishments After 1.5 years at Visible Alpha, I was promoted to the Software Engineer 2 position. My accomplishments during this time were -
Engineered the framework for adding Snowflake as a data delivery channel using Falcon, Python, Snowflake, MySQL, and AWS S3, increasing the generated revenue by 45% and reducing the Time To Value Built APIs to reduce the average tech-support turnaround time by 80% from 10 to 2 minutes Revamped the file dispatcher microservice to reduce the number of open SSH connections by 5X using Paramiko Implemented a dashboard to report daily file generation and dispatch metrics to aid Support Team in monitoring failures Performed Snowflake database replication over different regions and clouds Documented the projects using the Sphinx documentation generator Assisted the Infrastructure team with deployment issues I am happy to connect to talk about my work, so reach out to know more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visible Alpha - SE 1</title>
      <link>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/va-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 19:07:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/va-1/</guid>
      <description>Responsibilities/Accomplishments As a Software Engineer in the Data feed and APIs team, I -
Overcame architectural challenges associated with a monolithic design by implementing a microservice-based enterprise fintech ETL application. The solution delivers high-volume, real-time data to clients with low latency, using the latest technologies such as Django, MySQL, MongoDB, and Redis, driving $2 million in revenue Optimized file dispatch latency by 80% using RabbitMQ &amp;amp; Celery for asynchronous task execution (60 to 10 seconds) Designed REST APIs and added APIs and AWS S3 as data delivery channels to ease data consumption for clients Augmented error logging by leveraging the latest features of Sentry and by implementing a global logger, saving 25% of the team’s time spent on debugging and bug fixes Solved complex performance problems by resolving production issues, gaining exposure to dealing with large-scale software design issues, and avoiding performance bottlenecks Worked on projects through different phases of the software development life cycle including writing unit and automation tests and deploying projects on servers using Docker and Jenkins Wrote unit tests using the Pytest framework and increased unit test code coverage from 11% to 77% Carried out load and performance testing of the APIs using JMeter Set up a dev environment using Docker and Jenkins for dev testing Wrote backward compatible queries during MySQL version migration Highlights outside the realm of my role Augmented QA team&amp;rsquo;s automation test suite using Cucumber test framework and Behavioral Driven Development (BDD) Set up weekly meetings with the Product team manager to understand the product better and bridge the gap between the product and the dev team I am happy to connect to talk about my work, so reach out to know more!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IIT Bombay</title>
      <link>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/iit-bombay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 16:58:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/iit-bombay/</guid>
      <description>About As a Research Intern, I was working alongside Anshuman Dhuliya, a PhD student at IIT Bombay, on his project Synergistic Program ANalyzer (SPAN). My role was to contribute to the Front-end of SPAN - to create a source-to-source compiler that takes a high-level specification as input and transpiles it into its Python equivalent.
Problem SPAN required data flow analyses as an input and in Python language to apply those optimizations to an input program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastek</title>
      <link>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/mastek/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 03:57:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://himanshu808.github.io/experience/mastek/</guid>
      <description>Problem Mastek was using an internal help-desk application for their employees to log trouble tickets. This help-desk application was Desktop app and was quite cumbersome and difficult to use. Moreover, in certain situations, such as malfunctioning of keyboard or mouse, it became extremely difficult to raise a ticket. Employees had to log in to their PCs every time to view the ticket status.
Goal To improve the overall user experience of Mastek&amp;rsquo;s internal help-desk application.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
